Yeah.
응.
A quantum circuit is going to be the unit of value
quantum circuit은 비즈니스의 가치 단위가 될 거야
for your business the cubad is the unit of information
qubit은 정보의 단위고
but a circuit is the unit of computation
circuit은 연산의 단위야
so let's try to understand what is a quantum circuit
그럼 quantum circuit이 뭔지 이해해 보자
and let's look at its anatomy
그 구조를 살펴볼게
this is what a quantum circuit looks
quantum circuit은 이렇게 생겼어
like solicity composes into pieces the cubates
몇 가지 부분으로 나뉘는데 qubit은
are depicted by these horizontal lines in this case were depicting
이 수평선들로 표현돼 여기선 총
a circuit that has four cubits that you see
네 개의 qubit을 가진 circuit을 보여주고 있어
here shown now the gates are
지금 보이지 그리고 gate는
how we control the cubits
qubit을 제어하는 방법이야
and you read the gates from left to right
gate는 왼쪽에서 오른쪽으로 읽어
and the single cubit gates can be single
단일 qubit gate는 단일
cube of gaze or multi cubit gates
qubit gate이거나 다중 qubit gate야
you see there the controlled gate
거기서 controlled gate가 보이지
is that one which has the line between two of the cubits
두 qubit 사이에 선이 있는 게 그거야
and that's where the entangling operation is gonna happen
거기서 얽힘 연산이 일어나게 돼
and finally you have the measurement and the classical output
그리고 마지막으로 측정과 고전적 출력이 있어
and very importantly you run a circuit many times
아주 중요한 게, circuit은 여러 번 실행해
to get the result with the notion of shots
shot이라는 개념으로 결과를 얻는 거야
and so a shot counter which is a number of times
shot 카운터는 결과를 얻기 위해
you have to repeat a computation to get the result
연산을 반복해야 하는 횟수야
well
그럼
how do they look
어떻게 생겼냐고
let's look at how a two bit it's like
2비트가 어떻게 생겼는지 보자
that i was the picture before right introducing a face change
아까 그림에서 위상 변화를 소개했잖아
and i showed before a sea operation that performed that rotation
그 회전을 수행하는 연산을 아까 보여줬는데
that allows that to do that interference operation
그게 간섭 연산을 가능하게 해
so let's do a comparison between a classical circuit
그럼 고전 circuit과 비교해 보자
and a quantum circuit hearing a classical circuit would you
quantum circuit과 비교하면 고전 circuit에서는
witness here is that you don't get to see blue moons right
파란 달 같은 건 볼 수 없잖아
there's no rotations everything here is pink
회전이 없고 여기서는 다 분홍색이야
and that you got the single states
그리고 단일 상태들만 있어
that in these gays were seen windows fear
이 gate들에서 창문 같은 게 보이던 것들
but notice what a contrast is gonna look
그런데 quantum circuit을 실제로
like when we actually implement a quantum circuit
구현할 때 얼마나 대조적인지 봐봐
these are the actual circuits that we run in our quantum computers
이게 우리 양자 컴퓨터에서 실제로 실행하는 circuit이야
here that you can try as well
너도 한번 해볼 수 있어
the circuits that we are going to create
우리가 만들 circuit은
with the combination of the gates
gate들을 조합해서
generate the full complex amplitude
완전한 복소 진폭을
picture that i shared with you
아까 보여준 그림처럼 생성해
earlier why is that important
왜 그게 중요하냐면
because we can now generate these complex relationships
이제 qubit 간의 복잡한 관계를 위상 측면에서
between the cubits in terms of phases
생성할 수 있기 때문이야
and entanglement and then through the act of measurement
그리고 얽힘을 통해 측정 행위를 하면
we are able to collapse this massive amount
내부에서 일어나는 이 엄청난 양의
of computing that is happening inside into
연산을 붕괴시켜서
some important answer
중요한 답을 얻을 수 있어
and that is how we get finally to
그래서 결국 우리가
to the answer so we put inside by side just visually
답에 도달하는 거야 나란히 놓고 시각적으로만 봐도
you can get a sense that a classical circuit can
고전 circuit은 절대
never exploit the vast computational space
방대한 연산 공간을 활용할 수 없다는 걸 알 수 있어
that a quantum circuit can it's
quantum circuit은 할 수 있는데
is the best solicitions give you this intuition
이게 이 큰 상태에 접근할 수 있는 풍부함에 대한 직관을 줘
of the richness with which we can access this large state.
우리가 이 큰 상태에 얼마나 풍부하게 접근할 수 있는지 말이야
And the beautiful part of this is that we can
그리고 아름다운 점은
have many classes of circus to
다양한 종류의 circuit이 있어서
do different functions so
서로 다른 기능을 수행할 수 있다는 거야
for example this is a circuit
예를 들어 이건 circuit인데
that is designed to model financial risk
금융 리스크를 모델링하기 위해 설계된 거야
he is an example of a circuit
이건 circuit의 예인데
used to search and optimize problems
검색과 최적화 문제에 사용돼
and here is an example of a circuit that is used to
그리고 이건 circuit의 예인데
simulate a molecule an important
분자를 시뮬레이션하는 데 사용돼 중요한
take away as that you can design different circuits
핵심은 다양한 circuit을 설계할 수 있다는 거야
for different applications
용도에 따라 다르게
the circuits that we design are then captured
우리가 설계한 circuit은 그 다음
in software and kept as software
소프트웨어로 캡처되고 소프트웨어로 보관돼
and in our case we keep them in Qiskit
우리의 경우엔 Qiskit에 보관해
which is our open source development kit for quantum computing
Qiskit은 양자 컴퓨팅을 위한 오픈 소스 개발 키트야
this is one of the most widely used
이건 가장 널리 사용되는
software frameworks for quantum computing
양자 컴퓨팅 소프트웨어 프레임워크 중 하나야
and you can imagine building
그리고 circuit의 라이브러리를 구축하는 걸 상상할 수 있어
libraries of circuits that get embedded in
고전 프로그램에 내장되는 circuit 라이브러리를
classical programs that now combine the best of classical programming
고전 프로그래밍의 장점과
and the best of quantum power
양자 컴퓨팅의 장점을 결합하는 거야